Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of LGBTQ Rights Serials TAM.752
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of LGBTQ Rights Serials
1969-2001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM.752
2.1 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box, 2 half manuscript boxes, and 5 flat boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of LGBTQ Rights Serials groups 41 titles broadly relating to lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ) rights, published between 1969 and 2001, originally received by the Tamiment Library through subscriptions, donations, and as part of archival collections. The collection consists of incomplete runs of newspapers, newsletters, magazines, and bulletins, with a smaller quantity of one-off reports and catalogs, published by LGBTQ rights organizations, encompassing activist networks, academic institutions, and nonprofits. The serials provide contemporaneous coverage of a wide range of issues of concern to LGBTQ communities between the 1970s and 1990s, broadly addressing sexuality, gender, anti-gay violence and discrimination, health, and cultural portrayals of the LGBTQ community.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to LGBTQ Rights drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of LGBTQ Rights Serials groups 41 titles broadly relating to lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ) rights, published between 1969 and 2001, originally received by the Tamiment Library through subscriptions, donations, and as part of archival collections. The collection consists of incomplete runs of newspapers, newsletters, magazines, and bulletins, with a smaller quantity of one-off reports and catalogs, published by LGBTQ rights organizations, encompassing activist networks, academic institutions, and nonprofits. The serials provide contemporaneous coverage of a wide range of issues of concern to LGBTQ communities between the 1970s and 1990s, broadly addressing sexuality, gender, anti-LGBTQ violence and discrimination, health, and cultural portrayals of the LGBTQ community.
Among the topics addressed in the serials are sexuality, gender, anti-LGBTQ violence and legislation, housing and workplace discrimination, HIV/AIDS, gay pride demonstrations, arts, media, and the role of LGBTQ people within other political movements. Serials address LGBTQ rights in a variety of social movements including organized labor, peace activism, socialism, and anarchism and address the specific issues LGBTQ members of those communities faced. Local and regional serials include news and announcements related to demonstrations, local events, hate crimes, cases of discrimination, and state and municipal regulations. Serials in this collection were predominantly published in the United States by local and regional activist organizations. The bulk were published in New York, but publications from California, Washington, Massachusetts, Connecticut, and Michigan are also present. Serials in this collection do not provide much information on international LGBTQ issues, and only include a small number of international publications from the United Kingdom and Canada. Likewise, topics related to transgender rights and transgender communities are limited in this collection, as the bulk of periodicals were largely produced by lesbian and gay rights groups between the 1970s and 1990s.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of certain original materials, researchers may be required to consult microfilm copies, preservation photocopies, or digital images of material in this collection.
Gay rights movement.; Lesbians -- Employment -- United States; Gays -- Employment -- United States; Gender identity -- United States; AIDS activists -- United States.; Safe sex in AIDS prevention -- United States.; Civil rights -- United States.; Victims of hate crimes; Periodicals
- Big Apple Dyke News: Gay Press Association, New York, NY, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Chicago Gay Crusader: Chicago Gay Crusader, Chicago, IL, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Come Out Fighting: The Newspaper of the Lavender and Red Union: Lavender & Red Union, circa 1980s (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Come Out!: Gay Liberation Front of New York, New York, NY, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Dykes & Gorgons: Gutter Dyke Collective, Berkeley, CA, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Echo of Sappho: Sisters for Liberation, Brooklyn, NY, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Faggots and Faggotry: Faggots and Faggotry, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Gay Clone: Gay Men's Alliance, New York, NY, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Gay Community News: Gay Community News, Boston, MA, 1979-1982, 1987, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
- Gay Left: Gay Left Collective, London, England, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Gay Liberation: Red Butterfly Publication, New York, NY, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Gay Media Alliance News: Gay Media Alliance, Brooklyn, NY, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- GCC Newsletter: Community Multi-Service Center, Seattle, WA, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- GLBTF Newsletter: Gay, Lesbian, Bisexual Task Force / American Library Association, Chicago, IL, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8, Box 8, Folder 1)
- HUB Bulletin: Homophile Union of Boston, Boston, MA, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- In Production: Testing the Limits, New York, NY, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Join Hands: Join Hands, San Francisco, CA, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Lavender Left: Lavender Left, New York, NY, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lavender Woman: The Lavender Woman, Chicago, IL, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Lesbian and Gay Teachers Association: Lesbian and Gay Teachers Association, Brooklyn, NY, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lesbian Community Newsletter: United Feminists of Olympia, Olympia, WA, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Lesbian Contradiction: San Francisco Women's Centers, San Francisco, CA, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
- Lesbian Front: Chris Lundberg, Washington, DC, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Lesbians Rising: Hunter College, New York, NY, 1978, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Lights: Media Lights, Inc., Seattle, WA, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
- Mama Bear News & Notes: Mama Bears, Oakland, CA, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Matrix: Olympia's Feminist/Lesbian Newspaper: Matrix Collective, Olympia, WA, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
- Men's Center Publication: Men's Center, New York, NY, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Mother: Mother, Stanford, CA, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Motive: Motive, Inc., New York, NY, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- New York City News/New York City News Northeast Alive: The New York City News, New York, NY, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 1-8, Box 6, Folder 1)
- Newsletter of the Lavender Left: Lavender Left, New York, NY, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Out and About: Out and About, Seattle, WA, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- Outlook: Out/Look Foundation, San Francisco, CA, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Political Perspective of the Lavender & Red Union: Lavender & Red Union, Los Angeles, CA, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Proud: Sexual Minorities Center, Bellingham, WA, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Purple Star: Journal of Radical Lesbians: Ann Arbor Radical Lesbians, Ann Arbor, MI, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Rites magazine: Rites Publishing, Toronto, Canada, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Seattle Gay News: Seattle Gay News, Seattle, WA, 1983-1987 (Box 6, Folder 2-6, Box 7, Folder 1-8)
- Struttin' Up 5th: Christopher Street Liberation Day March and Rally, New York, NY, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Supporters of Silkwood: Supporters of Silkwood, Washington, DC, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- TDG: The Dorian Group, Seattle, WA, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8, Box 8, Folder 6)
- Witch's OS: New Moon Publications, Inc., Stamford, CT, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)